tournamentsoftware.com 2019-09-12

# Tournamentsoftware.com

### Privacy statement Visual Reality B.V.

Visual Reality B.V. (hereinafter: “Visual Reality” or “we”) values the protection of your personal data and transparency in relation thereto. This Privacy statement describes how we collect, share, use and/or otherwise process, information through which you can be identified or are identifiable (“personal data”), such within the meaning of the General Data Protection Regulation (“GDPR”).

#### Identity and contact

Visual Reality B.V.  
Comeniusstraat 5  
1817 MS Alkmaar  
The Netherlands  
T: [+31 (0)72-8200282](tel:0031728200282)  
E: [helpdesk@tournamentsoftware.com](mailto:helpdesk@tournamentsoftware.com)

#### Types of personal data and processing purposes

Visual Reality offers (software) products and related services for organising sports competitions and tournaments, and for providing clear insight in competition- and tournament details and statistics.

In order to provide and execute our services, we may collect and process the personal data of business contact persons of customers (in particular sports federations and sports associations). In this respect, we will process data such as name, gender, title/function (within the organisation), (business) email address and (business) telephone number. When we maintain a professional business relation with you or your organisation, we may incidentally approach you by email newsletter with information about our services or relevant developments in relation thereto. If you no longer want to receive such newsletters, you are able to opt-out at any time via a link in the email.

We also process personal data when you visit our website(s), and you apply for an online account in order to register online for tournaments and/or competitions. In this respect we will ask for data such as full name, gender, birth date and email address, and where applicable, membership number and rating skill.

If you register via the online account for participation in a tournament, we also require your banking details for processing payment of the registration fee.

In addition, if you participate or have participated in competitions and/or tournaments, your name and membership number will be displayed in results (for example, ‘ _head to head_ ’) and rankings.

If you visit our website(s), we store the Internet Protocol (IP)-address of your computer or tablet device. This technical information helps us to manage, maintain and protect our website. In order to optimise and improve the content and use of our website(s), we also collect data about the browsing behaviour on our website(s). In this respect, we make use of Google Analytics. This functionality is configured in a privacy-friendly manner. We have entered into a data processing agreement with Google, the IP-address is being anonymised and data are not shared with Google.

#### Minor children

Our website(s) and services are not necessarily intended for use by minor children. However, it may be possible that personal data of minor children are displayed in sport results or rankings, via our website(s). This usually results from publication thereof by the applicable sports federation or sports association of the child. If you observe the processing of personal data of a minor child without consent of the parent or guardian, please contact us via the contact details below.

#### Protection of personal data

We have taken adequate technical and organisational measures to protect your personal data in the best possible way against loss, unauthorised access, disclosure, change and misuse.

#### Personal data we share with third parties

Visual Reality only shares your personal data with third parties as far as necessary to provide our services or to comply with statutory obligations.

For example, if you have registered to participate in a tournament, we will share your personal data with the organising sports association. In this respect, any results of the tournament may subsequently be shared (by the organising sports association) with the relevant sports federation for publication in rankings. Our software products make this exchange of data technically possible, however, the (ultimate) responsibility in relation to the processing of the personal data in this regard rests with the sports federation or sports association (as the case may be).

Visual Reality has concluded data processing agreements with all sports federations, sports associations and other third parties ((sub-)processors) for the processing and sharing personal data in respect of its software and services.

Any personal data that are processed under the responsibility of Visual Reality as ‘controller’ will only be transferred to countries or third parties (such as an international sports federation) outside the European Economic Area (EEA), as far as necessary and in accordance with the statutory requirements in relation thereto.

#### Retention term

We retain your personal data no longer than is necessary for the purpose for which we have collected the personal data, or in correspondence with an applicable statutory retention term. You may at all times request the removal of your personal data. If the request for removal is permitted, your personal data will be removed without delay.

#### Request for inspection, correction and other rights

You also have the right to request for inspection, correction, completion or transfer of your personal data. Additionally, you may request us to limit certain processing, or to object to the processing of your personal data. Any such requests may be directed to us in writing or through email via the contact details below. After receipt, we will assess your request and respond thereto within the applicable statutory term of four weeks.

Where technically possible we will follow up on requests for correction or removal of personal details without delay. In cases where Visual Reality does not qualify as the ‘controller’, but as the ‘processor’ – of a specific sports federation or sports association – any requests for exercising certain rights (such as inspection, correction or removal) will need to be directed to the applicable sports federation or sports association. We will inform you when such situation occurs.

#### Contact – questions or complaints

Any questions, inquiries or complaints regarding the processing or protection of your personal data can be directed to us via email ([helpdesk@tournamentsoftware.com](mailto:helpdesk@tournamentsoftware.com)).

For completeness, we also note that you have the right to submit a complaint with the relevant data protection authority (for the Netherlands this is the “ _Autoriteit Persoonsgegevens_ ”).

#### Applicable law

This Privacy statement, as well as any disputes arising therefrom or in connection therewith, shall be exclusively governed by Dutch law.

#### Changes

We reserve the right to unitarily amend this Privacy Statement in order to ensure compliance with applicable laws and regulations. We recommend that you consult this Privacy Statement on a regular basis in order to be aware of potential changes or updates.

_Alkmaar, November 2018_
